Guide to the Papers of Robert B. McKay 1919-1990 MC.208
New York University Archives
Robert B. McKay Papers
1919-1990
New York University Archives
McKay, Robert B.
MC.208
41 Linear Feet in 59 boxes.
Robert B. McKay joined the faculty of New York University's School of Law in 1953. He became Associate Dean of the School of Law in 1963, and served as Dean from 1967 to 1975. McKay was the Director of the Program on Justice, Society and the Individual of the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies until 1983, when he returned to New York University to teach. The papers of Robert B. McKay include materials generated by McKay while serving a variety of directorial, professorial and public service functions, as well as supplemental research materials used by him.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Arrangement
Materials remain in their original order and grouped into one series. Additional material donated at a later date was added to the end of the file listing.
Biographical Note
Robert B. McKay was born August 11, 1919, in Wichita, Kansas, to Ruth and John McKay. Graduating with a B.S. from the University of Kansas in 1940, he joined the U.S. Army just before Pearl Harbor. He served in the Philippines, and by the time the war ended he had reached the rank of captain. He went on to earn his J.D. from Yale University in 1947. After completing law school he was employed as an attorney by the U.S. Department of Justice from 1947-1950, in the Appellate Division of the Office of Alien Property. He then moved to Emory University School of Law, where he taught as an Assistant and Associate Professor of Law from 1950-1953.
McKay joined the NYU Law Faculty in 1953, and after serving for four years as Associate Dean and Administrative Head of the Graduate Division, he became Dean in 1967. He succeeded Dr. Miguel A. de Capriles, who became Dean in 1964. McKay served in that position until 1975, and his strong leadership is credited with increasing NYU's prestige among American law schools. During a time of great unrest in higher education over the Vietnam War, McKay built an atmosphere of trust and communication between students and administration by giving student representatives a role in decision-making processes.
Taking a leave of absence from NYU in 1975, McKay served as Director of the Program on Justice, Society and the Individual at the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies until 1983. Throughout his career McKay was involved in a wide variety of legal causes and outside organizations. He served as the Chairman of the New York State Special Commission on Attica in 1972, Board Chairman of the New York Civil Liberties Union, President of the Legal Aid Society, and Chairman of the Citizens Union. He returned to NYU in 1983 to establish and teach courses in the increasingly important areas of professional responsibility and alternative dispute resolution.
Robert B. McKay retired from teaching in 1989. He died on July 13, 1990. He was survived by his two daughters, Kathryn and Sara. His wife, the former Sara Kate Warmack, predeceased McKay by three years.
Sources:
Profile: Robert B. McKay. NYU Law. Spring/Summer 1989
Robert McKay, 70, Legal Scholar Who Led 1971 Attica Panel, Dies. New York Times. July 14, 1990
Faculty Information: Professional and Biographical. New York Univeristy Office of Public Affairs. June, 1979
Press Release, New York University News Bureau. March 9, 1967
Press Release, New York University Press and Broadcast Services, Dec. 3, 1975
Custodial History
Transferred to University Archives by New York University School of Law.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials generated by McKay while serving a variety of directorial, professorial and public service functions. Materials include reports; correspondence; transcripts of speeches; clippings; periodicals; and articles and papers written by McKay.
Attica Correctional Facility; Law |x Study and teaching.; New York (State). Special Commission on Attica; Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies. Program on Justice, Society, and the Individual; Legal Aid Society (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I., 32332
  - Untitled, undated; 32862 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abram's Transition Committees, undated; 32861 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ABA Human Experimentation, undated; 32860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Humanities, undated; 32859 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32858 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32857 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32856 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32855 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32854 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1977; 32853 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1977; 32852 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1977; 32851 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - DISPAC Publication, undated; 32850 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Affirmative Action/MAIDEF, 1979-1981; 32849 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Bar Association, 1983-1989; 32848 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Aspen Institute - Workshop on Terrorism, 1977; 32847 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Assorted Manuals (3), undated; 32846 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NYS Ethics Commission, undated; 32845 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lecture at Washington University Law School, 1990; 32844 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McGeorge, undated; 32843 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - City Bar Mission to Northern Ireland, undated; 32842 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ADR - Misc. articles, clippings, etc, 1982-1987; 32841 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ADR - Misc., 1984-1988; 32840 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ADR - Misc., 1989; 32839 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ADR - Misc., 1982-1988; 32838 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ADR - Misc., undated; 32837 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CPR Category 1, 1988; 32836 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration Day, 1987; 32835 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ADR Correspondence, 1990; 32834 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Insurance Arbitration Forum, 1985; 32833 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Professional Article Dispute Resolution, undated; 32832 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Professional Article Dispute Resolution, 1989; 32831 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ABA Dispute Resolution Update, 1985; 32830 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - NIDR Reports, 1986-1987; 32829 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dispute Resolution Forum, 1983-1988; 32828 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Law School Exercises, undated; 32827 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Dispute Resolution Center, 1984-1985; 32826 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Managerial Judges, 1982; 32825 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Articles and Journals, undated; 32824 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution - Court Annexed Arbitration Program, 1979-1985; 32823 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fairshare/The Affiliate, 1983-1988; 32822 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clippings 1980's, undated; 32821 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Municipal Labor Committee, 1986; 32820 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1980s; 32819 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Pellerin/Milnor v. Dreher and Washex, 1987; 32818 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Court of Appeals, 1989; 32817 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 32816 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Attock - Enserch, 1985-1986; 32815 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Governor Malcolm Wilson -- Correspondence, Memos, Reports, etc, undated; 32814 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Aspen Institute, 1975-1986; 32813 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Aspent Institute, 1986-1987; 32812 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Political Activity and Legislative Employees, 1981-1990; 32811 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - NYS Blue Ribbon Commission, undated; 32810 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Federal Bar Council, undated; 32809 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Conrail - MTA arbitration, 1985; 32808 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ICC, undated; 32807 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Citizens Union, undated; 32806 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - South Africa Trip Correspondence, 1975; 32805 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Assorted Alternative Dispute Resolution Journals, undated; 32804 (Box 5)
  - Clippings, 1977-1978; 32803 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bakke and Beyond, 1977-1978; 32802 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1974-1976; 32801 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action/Minority Education, 1977-1979; 32800 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action/Minority Education, 1973-1977; 32799 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Equality Through Litigation, undated; 32798 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Council on Legal Education For Professional Responsibility, 1977-1982; 32797 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32796 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Speeches and Manuscripts, 1976; 32795 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New School Course Fall, 1977; 32794 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Conference on Philanthropy: Conference Attendance, 1975; 32793 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Affirmative Action Reports, 1976-1979; 32792 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Educational Audio Visual, Inc., 1974-1977; 32791 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Conference Material, 1976-1977; 32790 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Conference Material, Assorted, 1976; 32789 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Is That Really Fair?, 1978; 32788 (Box 6)
  - American Assembly, 1990; 32787 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ABA Special Committee on Professionalism, 1987-1989; 32786 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Rise of the Justice Industry and the Decline of Legal Ethics, undated; 32785 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ABA Standing Committee on Lawyer Competence, 1985-1990; 32784 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ABA Committee on the Profession, 1990; 32783 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1990; 32782 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Writings on Tort Reform, 1987-1988; 32781 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Attanasio, John B.: The Principle of Aggregate Autonomy and the Calabresian Approach to Strict Products Liability, undated; 32780 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Report of Visit to the Soviet Union, 1978; 32779 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Maryland S.B.A. Report of Special Commission on Law Practice Quality, 1988; 32778 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Resources for Legal Services, 1988; 32777 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Conference of Chief Justice, Lake Tahoe, 1989; 32776 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - ABA. TIPS. Product Liability., undated; 32775 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - ABA. TIPS. Product Liability: Clippings, 1987-1988; 32774 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Letters, 1989-1990; 32773 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Product Liability Legislation, 1988-1990; 32772 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Special Coordinating Committee on Professionalism, 1988; 32771 (Box 6)
  - Property and Casualty Insurance: Fact or Fantasy?, undated; 32770 (Box 6)
  - ABCNY Committee on ABA Goals, 1988; 32769 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Institute of Judicial Administration: Kenneth Starr, 1989; 32768 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Second Century Committee, 1989; 32767 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Judges Journal, 1987; 32766 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1984-1990; 32765 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Conference on Representation and Apportionment, 1980; 32764 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Aspen Institute Report on State Crimes, 1989; 32763 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ABA Special Coordinating Committee on Professionalism, 1989; 32762 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - ABA Misc. Speeches, etc, undated; 32761 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - ABA Consortium non Legal Services & the Public, 1988; 32760 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1989; 32759 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ABA Standing Committee on Professional Discipline, 1989; 32758 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - ABA Commission on Professionalism, 1988; 32757 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Judicial Conference of the Second Circuit, 1989; 32756 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - ABA Standing Committee on Lawyer Referral and Info Services, 1988; 32755 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Writings on Legal Ethics, 1989-1990; 32754 (Box 7, Folder 11a)
  - Miscellaneous Writings on Legal Ethics, 1988; 32753 (Box 7, Folder 11b)
  - Miscellaneous Writings on Legal Ethics, 1971-1984; 32752 (Box 7, Folder 11c)
  - Miscellaneous Writings on Legal Ethics, 1964-1985; 32751 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - NYSBA Committee to Improve the Availability of Legal Services, 1989; 32750 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Writings on Legal Education, 1978-1988; 32749 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990; 32748 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1989-1990; 32747 (Box 7, Folder 15a)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1989-1990; 32746 (Box 7, Folder 15b)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1989-1990; 32745 (Box 7, Folder 15c)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1990; 32744 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32743 (Box 7, Folder 15e)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board: Public Hearings, 1989; 32742 (Box 7)
  - Compendium of Law and Regulations: Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32741 (Box 7)
  - ABA Task Force on Law Schools and the Profession, 1990; 32740 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - National Judicial College, 1990; 32739 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - CPR Legal Program, 1965-1966; 32738 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Conduct, 1990; 32737 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - American Assembly, 1990; 32736 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - New York State Ethics Commission, undated; 32735 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - New York State Ethics Commission Correspondence, 1988-1989; 32734 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - New York State Ethics Commission Correspondence, 1988; 32733 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - New York State Ethics Commission Correspondence, 1989; 32732 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Manuals and Transcripts of Ethics Commission Meetings, 1988-1989; 32731 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - NYSBA-Lawyers in Public Service, 1986-1987; 32730 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1989-1990; 32729 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Report to Centre for Applied Legal Studies, 1989; 32728 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1987-1990; 32727 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1987-1990; 32726 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1986-1987; 32725 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1986-1988; 32724 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1986-1987; 32723 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution Seminar, 1986-1988; 32722 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32721 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1990; 32720 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - ABA Articles and Correspondence, 1987-1990; 32719 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - ABA Articles and Correspondence, 1987-1990; 32718 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lawyer Conduct and Discipline, 1988-1990; 32717 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - CPR Legal Program, 1990; 32716 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - CPR Legal Program, 1990; 32715 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Civil Rights Act, 1990; 32714 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1989-1990; 32713 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Articles and Correspondence, 1989-1990; 32712 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - McKay Publications and Speeches, 1965-1987; 32711 (Box 10)
  - Lawyer Conduct and Discipline, 1988-1990; 32710 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1990; 32709 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1990; 32708 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Regan v. Wald, 1983; 32707 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Closing the Watergate, 1968-1977; 32706 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Closing the Watergate, 1976-1977; 32705 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Closing the Watergate, 1976-1977; 32704 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - ADR Articles, 1989-1990; 32703 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - ADR Articles, 1989-1990; 32702 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights, 1981-1982; 32701 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Supreme Court and Judicial Branches, 1968-1982; 32700 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Supreme Court and Judicial Branches, 1978-1982; 32699 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Supreme Court and Judicial Branches, undated; 32698 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Articles, 1970-1990; 32697 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - McKay Publications and Speeches, 1968-1990; 32696 (Box 12)
  - Manville, 1989; 32695 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Manville, 1988-1990; 32694 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Manville (binder), 1988; 32693 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Manville, 1988; 32692 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Manville, 1989-1990; 32691 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Manville, 1990; 32690 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Manville, 1988-1990; 32689 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Manville, 1989-1991; 32688 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Manville, 1989; 32687 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Manville, 1989-1990; 32686 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Manville, 1988-1989; 32685 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1989; 32684 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - ABA Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1989-1990; 32683 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), 1985-1986; 32682 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), 1983-1987; 32681 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), 1980-1983; 32680 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), 1987-1989; 32679 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), 1989; 32678 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), undated; 32677 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Center for Public Resources (CPR), undated; 32676 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - City Bar Association, Human Rights Mission to Singapore and Malaysia, July 1989, undated; 32675 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-1990; 32674 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1990; 32673 (Box 15)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of NY Continuing Legal Education, undated; 32672 (Box 15)
  - Dispute Management Inc. Training, undated; 32671 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1989; 32670 (Box 16)
  - NYS Ethics Commission, undated; 32669 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - NYS Ethics Commission (binder), 1990; 32668 (Box 17)
  - NYS Ethics Commission Investigations (binder), 1990; 32667 (Box 17)
  - American Bar Association (hardcover), 1974; 32666 (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt, Hon. Arthur T., 1952-1953; 32665 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Chief Justice Vanderbilt-to others, undated; 32664 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - NYU Bulletins, 1951-1952; 32663 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Vanderbilt, Hon. Arthur T., 1953-1954; 32662 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt, Hon. Arthur T., 1954-1955; 32661 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Vanderbilt, Hon. Arthur T., 1955; 32660 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - White House talking points (binder), undated; 32659 (Box 17)
  - 25th Anniversary of Graduation, Law School Class of 1894, 1919; 32658 (Box 18)
  - Academic Attire, undated; 32657 (Box 18)
  - Letter (enclosed with Academic Attire), 1970; 32656 (Box 18)
  - Manville, undated; 32655 (Box 19)
  - Arbitration, 1987-1990; 32654 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - CPR Practice Guide, 1989-1990; 32653 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - CPR Coursebook, 1990; 32652 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR), 1985; 32651 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - ADR Conferences/Centers, 1982-1985; 32650 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - CPR Legal Program - ADR, 1986-1990; 32649 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - CPR Legal Program, 1987-1990; 32648 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - ADR: Handbook for Judges (Manual), 1987; 32647 (Box 20)
  - ADR Articles and Notes, 1989-1990; 32646 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - ADR Clippings, 1989-1990; 32645 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Dispute Resolution First-Aid Kit for Attorneys, 1989; 32644 (Box 20)
  - Stallman Correspondence, 1984; 32643 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - National Conference on the Lawyer's Changing Role in Resolving Disputes (1 of 2), 1982; 32642 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - National Conference on the Lawyer's Changing Role in Resolving Disputes (2 of 2), 1982; 32641 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - ABA MAP Program Models and Packages, undated; 32640 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - ABA MAP Program Models and Packages, undated; 32639 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - National Council on Crime and Deliquency (NCCD), 1989; 32638 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32637 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1989; 32636 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32635 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32634 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32633 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1988-1989; 32632 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32631 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32630 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32629 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32628 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Finance Board, 1989; 32627 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - New Jersey Election Law Enforcement Commission, 1986-1988; 32626 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Legal Education and Admission to the Bar, 1989; 32625 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Criminal Justice, 1989-1990; 32624 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Charter Revision Commission, 1989; 32623 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Committee on the Profession, 1988-1990; 32622 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Minorities in the Profession - Chair, 1990; 32621 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Professionalism, 1988; 32620 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Survey of Lawyer Disciplinary Procedures in the United States, 1984; 32619 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Evaluation of Lawyer State Bar Disciplinary Systems, 1978-1988; 32618 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Evaluation of Lawyer State Bar Disciplinary Systems, 1988; 32617 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Committee for Modern Courts, 1989-1990; 32616 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - National Council on Crime and Deliquency (NCCD), 1990; 32615 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on Human Rights, 1989-1990; 32614 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Vera (Northern Ireland), 1990; 32613 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Sentencing, 1988-1989; 32612 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Sentencing, 1984-1990; 32611 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - National Judicial College, 1990; 32610 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - National Judicial College, 1989-1990; 32609 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Supreme Court Reports of Special Master, No. 74, 1985-1988; 32608 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous ADR, 1990; 32607 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1989; 32606 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - National Judicial College ABA-UNR, 1986-1994; 32605 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Bar Associations and Info, 1988-1990; 32604 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - N.Y.S. Special Committee on Continuing Legal Education, 1990; 32603 (Box 23)
  - ABA Fifteenth National Conference on Lawyers' Professional Responsibility, 1989; 32602 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous ABA, 1988-1990; 32601 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - NYC Campaign Finance Board, 1990; 32600 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1987-1990; 32599 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Board of Estimate Committee, 1986; 32598 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Citizens Union / Charter Revision, 1987-1988; 32597 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Election Law Seminar, 1988; 32596 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Legal Education / Affirmative Action, 1971-1981; 32595 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Manville Property Damage Settlement Trusts, 1986-1987; 32594 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Manville Property Damage Settlement Trusts, 1987; 32593 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Adversary Process Workshop, 1977-1978; 32592 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - ADR Teaching Materials, 1984-1989; 32591 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Articles and Correspondence, 1984-1990; 32590 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on Lawyer Professionalism, 1988; 32589 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Private Dispute Resolution Misc. Materials, 1988-1989; 32588 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1987-1989; 32587 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Commission on Evaluation of Disciplinary Enforcement, 1989; 32586 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Ronde vs Regents, 1980; 32585 (Box 24, Folder 18)